Rizki Perdana Bowo Laksono

Yogyakarta, 55242 | +62 896 0136 1061 | perdana.rizki16@gmail.com

About Me

Having experience in the field of software development and always interested in developing an idea into an applied application that has value. I have an interest in a career in the finance and technology sector.

Competence & Skill

- Backend (Ruby, Node JS, PHP, Python)
- Database (Postgresql, Mysql, MongoDB)
- Frontend (React JS, Vue JS, Jquery)
- Rest Framework (Grape, Swagger)

Work Experience

PT. Lentera Bangsa Benderang / Binar Academy (Jakarta, Indonesia)

Backend Engineer (August 2021 - Current)

- Utilizing Ruby On Rails to implement working API functions for mobile, website, and services.
- Creating unit tests using Rspec.
- Working with databases and ORM.
- Developing using Linux environment, Git, and Docker to keep application consistency and maintainability.

PT. Gamatechno Indonesia (Yogyakarta, Indonesia)

Backend Engineer Products (December 2020 - July 2021)

- Build REST API using PHP Lumen and Codeigniter.
- Working with unit tests.
- Maintaining internal PHP framework.

Quality Assurance (February 2020 - December 2020)

- Responsibility to testing applications on mobile, desktop, and website.
- Doing API Testing using Postman.
- Doing functional tests through positive tests and negative testing.
- Creating documentation for UAT.

PT. Diginet Media (Yogyakarta, Indonesia)

Backend Engineer (September 2014 - January 2016)

- Developing websites using PHP frameworks such as Laravel, Yii, and Codeigniter.
- Utilizing MySql and Postgresql as primary databases.
- Developing clean and functional code using microservice.

Education

Yogyakarta State University (2016-2020)

Bachelor of Accounting

- Developing Roomania app (room booking app) as contestant app for CPPBT (Calon Perusahaan Pemula Berbasis Teknologi/ Prospective Technology-Based Startup Company) on 2018.
- Becoming IT Leader Division on KSPM (Komunitas Studi Pasar Modal/Capital Market Study Community)

Latest Project

Budget Tracker API: spendor (March 2021-current)

Lead Developer

- Develop a personal budgeting management system that can be used to monitor expenses every month, and has a data recap feature per category and graphs every month.
- Applications are built with Vue and Java spring boot.

Government Openness API: instansiku (November 2021-current)

Lead Developer

- Develop a transparency system for central and local government throughout Indonesia.
- The application uses the MEVN stack and aims to increase the transparency of government information to the public.